Guide to the Olga Rudge Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Correspondence, 1904-89; Series II; 29.5; (60 boxes)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Neame, Alan to Chute, Desmond, 1951 Apr 29 (Box 92, Folder 2402)
    - New York City Planning Commission to Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1968 Mar 22 (Box 92, Folder 2403)
    - O'Grady, Desmond to [Rachewiltz, Mary de] (Box 92, Folder 2404)
    - Ohannessian, Griselda to New Directions, 1976 Nov 18 (Box 92, Folder 2405)
    - Ojetti, Fernando to Chigi-Saracini, Guido, conte, 1960 Jul 25 (Box 92, Folder 2406)
    - Owen, Peter to Moore, A.V., 1965 Sep 22 (Box 92, Folder 2407)
    - Pearce, Donald R. to Chigi-Saracini, Guido, conte, 1953 Dec 22 (Box 92, Folder 2408)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes to Pound, Dorothy, 1961 Oct 4 (Box 92, Folder 2409)
    - Pitkethly, Lawrence to Bolzoni, Roberto, 1982 Jan 28 (Box 92, Folder 2410)
    - Pound, Dorothy to Bacigalupo, [Frieda], 1947 Feb 13 (Box 92, Folder 2411)
    - Pound, Dorothy to Chute, Desmond (Box 92, Folder 2412)
    - Pound, Dorothy to Rachewiltz, Mary de (photograph), 1949 Jun 24 (Box 92, Folder 2413)
    - Pound, Omar to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1975 Mar 19 (Box 92, Folder 2414)
    - Preston, Percy to Binzen, Joan, 1980 Oct 30 (Box 92, Folder 2415)
    - Quinn, Bernetta to Fitzgerald, Joan, 1972 Aug 18 (Box 92, Folder 2416)
    - Rachewiltz, Boris to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1962, 1972 (Box 92, Folder 2417-18)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Somers-Cocks, Blanche, 1954 Jul 20 (Box 92, Folder 2419)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Duller, Hans, 1966 Oct 7 (Box 92, Folder 2420)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to du Sautoy, Peter, 1976 May 21 (Box 92, Folder 2421)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to H. D., 1950 Aug 26 (Box 92, Folder 2422)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Macleod, Joseph Gordon, 1965 Jun 8 (Box 92, Folder 2423)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Mertens, Mr., [1963] (Box 92, Folder 2424)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Ottone, Piero, 1976 Jun 2 (Box 92, Folder 2425)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Pescetto, Alberto, 1958 (Box 92, Folder 2426)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Pound, Omar, 1975 Mar 8 (Box 92, Folder 2427)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Ransom, Harry, 1964 Jun 19 (Box 92, Folder 2428)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Somers-Cocks, Blanche, [1963] (Box 92, Folder 2429)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de to Unidentified [Avvocato], 1972 Mar-May (Box 92, Folder 2430)
    - La Radio Italia to Zaffrani, Gian Franco, [1949 Sep 25] (Box 92, Folder 2431)
    - Ritter, Fernando to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1972 Nov 3 (Box 92, Folder 2432)
    - Ritzinger, John and Vonnie to Pound, Dorothy, 1970 Sep 18 (Box 92, Folder 2433)
    - Ramsey, Gloria to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1962 Sep 17 (Box 92, Folder 2434)
    - Roux, Dominique de to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1965 May 2 (Box 92, Folder 2435)
    - Roux, Dominique de to Scheiwiller, Vanni, 1964 Apr 20 (Box 92, Folder 2436)
    - Roux, Marie to Vannini, Armando, 1950 Sep 2 (Box 92, Folder 2437)
    - Ruffini, Nina to Pescetto, Alberto, 1969 Jun 15 (Box 92, Folder 2438)
    - Saunders, Chas to Pound, Dorothy, 1970 May 23 (Box 92, Folder 2439)
    - Serly, Tibor to Laughlin, James, 1977 Nov 24 (Box 92, Folder 2440)
    - Seward, William W. to Pound, Ezra, 1964 Oct 7 (Box 92, Folder 2441)
    - Shore, Donald to Laughlin, James, 1969 Jun 8 (Box 92, Folder 2442)
    - Simmons, Charles to Nebolsine, Arcadi, 1971 Aug 2 (Box 92, Folder 2443)
    - Singh, G. to Cohn, Mr., 1989 Mar 1 (Box 92, Folder 2444)
    - Singh, G. to Pound, Dorothy, 1966 Nov 26 (Box 92, Folder 2445)
    - Singh, G. to T.L.S., 1972 Jul 6 (Box 92, Folder 2446)
    - Smith, Elizabeth W. to Pound, Dorothy (Box 92, Folder 2447)
    - Snyder, Robert to Chigi-Saracini, Guido, conte, 1959 Sep 26 (Box 92, Folder 2448)
    - Snyder, Robert to Fitzgerald, Joan, 1969, 1972 (Box 92, Folder 2449)
    - Somers-Cocks, Blanche to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1964 Oct 8 (Box 92, Folder 2450)
    - Stock, Noel to Pound, Dorothy (Box 92, Folder 2451)
    - Storch, Laila to Pescetto, Alberto, 1955, 1958 (Box 92, Folder 2452)
    - Storrs, Ronald to Chigi-Saracini, Guido, conte, 1951 Oct 25 (Box 92, Folder 2453)
    - Sucherman, Stuart to Lippi, Simonetta, 1968 Sep 23 (Box 92, Folder 2454)
    - Tallone, Alberto to Mazzinghi, Mr., 1972 Feb 16 (Box 92, Folder 2455)
    - Terry, Caryl S. to Pound, Dorothy, 1970 Feb 4 (Box 92, Folder 2456)
    - Vannini, Armando to Dadone, Ugo, 1961 Mar-Apr (Box 92, Folder 2457)
    - Vannini, Armando to Unidentified, 1937 Aug 11 (Box 92, Folder 2458)
    - Vegoith, André to Rudge, Edgar, [1911 Mar 17] (Box 92, Folder 2459)
    - Villari, Luigi to Pound, Dorothy, 1948 May 25 (Box 92, Folder 2460)
    - Von Valkenburgh, Lee to Pound, Dorothy, 1963 Jun 24 (Box 92, Folder 2461)
    - Williams, William Carlos to Pound, Dorothy, 1948 Jun 11 (Box 92, Folder 2462)
    - "Brigit" to Pound, Dorothy, 1962 Jul 10 (Box 92, Folder 2463)
    - "E.L.S." to Pound, Dorothy, 1948 Jun 6 (Box 92, Folder 2464)
    - "Elizabeth" to Menecle, Toni, 1955 Aug 16 (Box 92, Folder 2465)
    - "Miss Cora" to Rachewiltz, Walter, 1953 Apr 5 (Box 92, Folder 2466)
    - "Nina" to von Mendelssohn, Francesco (Box 92, Folder 2467)
    - "Raffaela" to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1953 Aug 10 (Box 92, Folder 2468)
    - "Rose Marie" to Pound, Dorothy, 1948 Jun 10 (Box 92, Folder 2469)
    - [S..., Roberto] to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1969 Feb 8 (Box 92, Folder 2470)
    - Unidentified to Fitzgerald, Joan, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2471)
    - Unidentified to Gonigal, A.M., 1909 Jun 30 (Box 92, Folder 2472)
    - Unidentified to Novello, Antonio, 1952 Apr 9 (Box 92, Folder 2473)
    - Unidentified to Pound, Dorothy (Box 92, Folder 2474)
    - Unidentified to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1963 Sep 7 (Box 92, Folder 2475)
    - Unidentified to Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1965, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 2476)
    - Unidentified to Way, Peter, 1976 Oct 24 (Box 92, Folder 2477)
    - (photocopy)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2478)
    - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2479)
- Notebooks, 1966-86; Series III; 4.5; (9 boxes)
  Series III, Notebooks, is housed in Boxes 93-102 and is divided into two sections. The first, I Ching Notebooks, contains daily records kept by Olga Rudge and is chronologically arranged. The second, Research notebooks: Ezra Pound, consists of material gathered by Olga Rudge in her later years. These have been alphabetically arranged by title and/or subject.
  - I CHING NOTEBOOKS
    - "I Ching", 1966-1973 Jan (Box 93, Folder 2480-91)
    - "I Ching", 1973 Jan-1975 Aug (Box 94, Folder 2492-2508)
    - "I Ching", 1975 Sep-1977 Oct (Box 95, Folder 2509-25)
    - "I Ching", 1977 Oct-1981 Mar (Box 96, Folder 2526-43)
    - "I Ching", 1981 Apr-1983 Apr (Box 97, Folder 2544-58)
    - "I Ching", 1983 May-1985 Mar (Box 98, Folder 2559-72)
    - "I Ching", 1985 Mar-1986 Apr (Box 99, Folder 2573-80)
  - RESEARCH NOTEBOOKS: EZRA POUND
    - "American background": information on early life of Pound, notes on Rudge, and letter drafts (Box 99, Folder 2581)
    - "Cantos"
      See also: Series IV, Cantos, Box 110, folder 2788
      - Name index (Box 99, Folder 2582)
      - Name index (Box 99, Folder 2583)
      - Notes on CX-CXVII, 1968 (Box 99, Folder 2584)
    - Chinese ideograms, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2585)
    - "Diary 1931 (copy)", n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2586)
    - "Dreams": copies of I Ching entries for 1969-72, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 2587)
    - "Films--to be developed; re (missing) Hohenacker film; re Photos" with letter drafts, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2588)
    - Letter drafts, 1970, 1974? (Box 100, Folder 2589)
    - Letter drafts and reminiscences (Box 100, Folder 2590)
    - "Letters--addresses--1970-71 and on (and earlier)" (Box 100, Folder 2591)
    - "List of books with notes and/or corrections signed by E.P.; List of books signed for E.P. by authors", 1973? (Box 100, Folder 2592)
    - "Mentions for and against...also Poems for EP": alphabetical notebook (Box 100, Folder 2593)
    - "Notes, 1981" (Box 100, Folder 2594)
    - Notes on exhibitions concerning Pound (Box 100, Folder 2595)
    - Notes on people, places and institutions connected with Pound (Box 100, Folder 2596)
    - " Orientamenti ": suggested corrections, 1978 (Box 100, Folder 2597)
    - " Paideuma (ed. Prof Terrell)": notes on volumes 1-2, [1972-73?] (Box 100, Folder 2598)
    - "Quotes from Books: Markings, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 2599)
    - "S. Ambrogio 1968: Notes EP": includes list of books annotated by Pound (Box 100, Folder 2600)
    - "Summer 1978": letter drafts, addresses, and notes on books (Box 100, Folder 2601)
    - "To OR: '45. '30. '31.": name index to letters (Box 100, Folder 2602)
    - "Transcriptions EP": annotated copies of notebooks kept by Pound 1962-69, 1974, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2603)
    - Transcripts of Cantos lxxii and lxxiii, letter drafts, and miscellaneous notes, 1974, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2604)
    - Transcripts of correspondence
      - Letters of Olga Rudge to Ezra Pound, 1928 (Box 101, Folder 2605)
      - Letters of Olga Rudge, 1945, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2606)
      - Excerpts of Pound's 1946 letters to Rudge and copy of 1970 I Ching (Box 101, Folder 2607)
      - Excerpts of Pound's 1947 letters to Rudge and transcripts of Teddy Rudge's diaries for 1914-15 (Box 101, Folder 2608)
      - Excerpts of Rudge's 1947-51 and transcripts of 1945 letterbook (Box 101, Folder 2609-10)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 2611-17)
- Personal Papers, 1916-89; Series IV; 8; (16 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers, is housed in Boxes 102-24 and arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Address books, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2618-21)
  - Address slips, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 2622-27)
  - Agendas, 1926-70 (Box 103, Folder 2628-48)
  - Agendas, 1972-87 (Box 104, Folder 2649-51)
  - Architectural drawings, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2652)
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2653-55)
    See also: Oversize, Box 157, Folder 3702
  - Biographical information
    - Autobiographical notes, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2656-57)
    - Family and friends (Box 105, Folder 2658)
    - Medical information, 1929-81, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2659)
    - Miscellaneous lists and notes (Box 105, Folder 2660-62)
  - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2663-73)
  - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2674)
  - Diaries, 1931, 1934, 1943 (Box 106, Folder 2675-77)
  - Greeting cards, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2678)
  - I Ching notes and cards, 1952, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2679)
  - Inventories
    - Books, manuscripts and tapes, 1972-88, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2680-85)
    - Household items, 1945, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2686-88)
  - Invitations and announcements, 1949-89, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2689-92)
  - Invitations and announcements, 1949-89, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2693-95)
  - Itineraries and schedules, 1965-85, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2696-97)
  - Legal papers
    - Attestato della residenza, 1941 Sep 10 (Box 107, Folder 2698)
    - Petition in favor of Pound by citizens of Rapallo, 1948 Oct 10 (Box 107, Folder 2699)
    - Procura concerning the death of Lester Littlefield, [1973] (Box 107, Folder 2700)
    - Residence permits, 1936-82 (Box 107, Folder 2701)
    - Travel permit from the Allied Military Government, 1945 Oct 17 (Box 107, Folder 2702)
    - Wills, 1953-72 (Box 107, Folder 2703)
  - Letter drafts, unidentified and incomplete, [ca. 1955-88?] (Box 107, Folder 2704-18)
  - Lists: names, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2719)
  - Lists: to do, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2720-23)
  - Memorabilia
    - Astrological wheel and prediction (Box 108, Folder 2724)
    - Book cover with coat of arms, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2725)
    - Bookmark, n.d.
    - Calendars, 1923, 1958 (Box 108, Folder 2726-27)
    - Ferns from Battle Abbey, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2728)
    - Flowers
      - "Mussolini bouquet", 1927 Feb 24 (Box 108, Folder 2729)
      - "Brancusi", 1933 Jul
      - "Elizabeth Beerbohm", 1959 Dec (Box 108, Folder 2730)
      - "Mimy!", n.d.
    - Funeral ribbons, 1972
      See: Oversize, Box 157, Folder 3703
    - Hair ("Mary's baby-hair"), [1926?] (Box 108, Folder 2731)
    - Hair and edelweiss (Box 108, Folder 2732)
    - Leaves, [1890s], n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2733-35)
    - Maple seeds, 1947 (Box 108, Folder 2736)
    - Matchbooks, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2737)
    - Miniature banners left on Ezra Pound's grave, 1978 (Box 108, Folder 2738)
    - Party favor, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2739)
    - Seed packets, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2740)
    - Stamps, 1936-65, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2741-42)
    - Sugar packets, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2743)
    - Tooth (Mary de Rachewiltz), n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2744)
    - Violin string, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2745)
    - Wallets, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2746-47)
    - Wax seal (profile of Olga Rudge), n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2748)
  - Notes on books, 1957-81, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2749-57)
  - Notes on correspondence (Box 109, Folder 2758-61)
  - Notes on Pound
    - Biographical, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2762-67)
    - Exhibits and tributes
      - "Ezra Pound and His World" (Box 109, Folder 2768)
      - "Ezra Pound: the Last Ten Years", 1980-82, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2769-70)
      - "Friends of Ezra Pound in Venice", 1976, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2771-72)
      - "Micro Mostra Poundiana", 1977 (Box 110, Folder 2773-74)
      - "A Quiet Requiem for Ezra Pound", 1973 (Box 110, Folder 2775)
      - Yeats-Pound memorial, 1981, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2776)
      - Unidentified and miscellaneous (Box 110, Folder 2777-81)
    - Funeral, [1972] (Box 110, Folder 2782)
    - Medical care, 1962-69, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2783-84)
    - Quotations and comments, 1966-70, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2785)
    - Radio speeches, 1942-84, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2786-87)
    - Writings
      - Cantos, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2788-91)
      - Other works, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2792)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2793)
  - Notes: miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2794)
  - Obituaries, 1950-76, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2795-97)
  - Passports, 1928-74 (Box 111, Folder 2798-99)
  - Postcards, [1916-80, n.d.] (Box 111, Folder 2800)
  - Postcards, [1916-80, n.d.] (Box 112, Folder 2801)
  - Postcards, [1916-80, n.d.] (Box 113, Folder 2802)
  - Rachewiltz, Mary de
    - Journal notebook, 1945-47 (Box 114, Folder 2803)
    - Report card, 1941 (Box 114, Folder 2804)
    - "Rules for Mary", n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2805)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2806)
  - Stenotype lessons, [ca. 1930] (Box 114, Folder 2807)
  - Tickets and ticket stubs, 1966-79, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2808-09)
  - Transcripts of correspondence (Box 114, Folder 2810-11)
  - Writings
    "Antonio Vivaldi" (article for Grove's Dictionary of Music )
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2812)
    - Typescript carbon, n.d.
    - "Antonio Vivaldi, musico di violino", n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2813)
    - "The Blue Spill"
      - First draft: typescript and typescript carbon, with corrections by Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, incomplete, [ca. 1930?] (Box 115, Folder 2814-16)
      - Second draft: typescript and typescript carbon, with corrections by Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, and plot notes by Pound, incomplete, [ca. 1930?] (Box 115, Folder 2817-23)
      - Miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2824)
    - "Cantos d'Ezra Pound" (translation of article by Louis Zukofsky): typescript carbon (Box 115, Folder 2825)
    - "Il 'Chorus' della Juditha Triumphans di Antonio Vivaldi": offprint, 1962 Jul (Box 115, Folder 2826)
    - "The Difficulties of Knowing Vivaldi": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2827)
    - "Dr. W. Gillies Whittaker e la musicologia Brittanica" (for Broletto )
      - Typescript outline and notes, by Ezra Pound, annotated by him, 1938 (Box 115, Folder 2828)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected by Olga Rudge and Ezra Pound, [1938] (Box 115, Folder 2829)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected by Olga Rudge and Ezra Pound, signed by Olga Rudge, [1938] (Box 115, Folder 2830)
    - "England's War in France" (translation of chapters 1 and 2 of Salvator Aponte's "La Guerra degli Inglesi in Francia")
      - Typescript, with corrections by Ezra Pound, [1940s] (Box 115, Folder 2831)
      - Typescript carbon, [1940s] (Box 115, Folder 2832)
    - "Ezra Pound in Spoleto:" typescript carbons and corrected proofs (Box 115, Folder 2833)
    - "The Holy Face" (translation of a part of Enrico Pea's Moscardino, "Il Volto Santo")
      - Manuscript, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2834-36)
      - Manuscript, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2837-38)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2839-41)
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2842)
      - Miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2843)
    - "If Little Society cannot use my notes..." typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2844)
    - "If This be Treason...... " reprint of the 1948 pamphlet edited by Rudge, 1983 (Box 115, Folder 2845)
    - "Japanese Poetry" (translation of an article by an unidentified author): typescript carbons, with corrections and annotations by Ezra Pound (Box 115, Folder 2846)
    - "Lettere di Antonio Vivaldi"
      - Transcripts of letters: typescript and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 116, Folder 2847)
      - Translation draft notebook (Box 116, Folder 2848)
      - Translations: typescript, corrected by Olga Rudge and Ezra Pound (Box 116, Folder 2849)
      - Translations: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2850)
      - Miscellaneous pages: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2851)
      - The Listener, p. 834, 1936 Oct 28
      - See: Oversize, Box 157, folder 3704
    - "The Lexicography of Enrico Pea": manuscript translation of Italian? original, annotated and corrected by Desmond Chute (Box 116, Folder 2852)
    - "Un movimento filosofico-religioso!" manuscript notes and typescript carbon (signed O. Vivaldi) (Box 116, Folder 2853)
    - "Per una biblioteca microfotografica", 1939 Jul 30
    - [Review of Catologo numerico tematico delle composizioni di Antonio Vivaldi, by Mario Rinaldi]: typescript carbon, [1945?] (Box 116, Folder 2854)
    - "Solo gli uomini in Casa Savoia": typescript, corrected. With: excerpts from the Journal of Alice James, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2855)
    - "To Friends and Enemies of Ezra Pound:" manuscript draft, corrected (Box 116, Folder 2856)
    - "Venice and Vivaldi", 1938 Jan (Box 116, Folder 2857)
    - "Villa Brichieri-Colombi, at Belloguardo" (translation of an article in Vie d'Italie ): typescripts, [1952?] (Box 116, Folder 2858)
    - "Vivaldi: La sua posizione nella storia della musica", n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2859)
    - Untitled piece beginning "Ezra Pound died in his sleep..." typescript drafts, corrected, 1976 (Box 116, Folder 2860)
    - Untitled piece beginning "Nello studia della musica..." and marked "Broletto, 1938": typescript carbon (Box 116, Folder 2861)
    - Unidentified typescript, incomplete, n.d.
  - Writings of Others
    - Aldrich, Mike
      - "Incense Set": mimeograph, 1967 (Box 117, Folder 2862)
    - Antheil, George
      - "Jazz Is Music": printed, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2863)
    - Arnold, Kenneth
      - The House of Bedlam: typescript photocopy, 1977 (Box 117, Folder 2864)
    - Awisus, Sabine
      - "The Poet Professionally Cross- Examined" (review of Eva Hesse's Vonn und Wahnsinn ) typescript annotated, [1978?] (Box 117, Folder 2865)
    - Boschetti, Piero
      - "La Pantera" and "Der Panther": typescript carbon, with note, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 2866)
    - Bridson, D. G.
      - "Ezra Pound's 'Four Steps': typescript carbon, corrected (Box 117, Folder 2867)
    - Connolly, Cyril
      - "Pound in Venice": galley, corrected, signed (Box 117, Folder 2868)
    - Cournos, John
      - "...A Tide in the Affairs of Men...": typescript, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2869)
    - Diggins, John
      - Mussolini and Fascism: the View from America: photocopy annotated, [1972?] (Box 117, Folder 2870)
    - Elagin, Ivan
      - Translations from Pound: typescript photocopy, [1971?] (Box 117, Folder 2871)
    - Engel, Ilse
      - "Story of a Meeting with Ezra Pound": typescript, 1970 (Box 117, Folder 2872)
    - Farragher, Shaun
      - [Poems]: typescript photocopy, annotated and autographed, [1974] (Box 117, Folder 2873)
    - Fischer, W. L.
      - "Topological Invariants of Matrices": offprint, 1970 (Box 117, Folder 2874)
    - Fisher, Margaret
      - "Ti sistemo io!": typescript, 1983 (Box 117, Folder 2875)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert
      - "Memorandum for Mary": typescript annotated, 1954 Aug (Box 117, Folder 2876)
    - Fuller, Buckminister
      - "Love is both inclusive...": typescript photocopy, 1971 (Box 117, Folder 2877)
    - Gallup, Donald
      - "'Boobliography' and Ezra Pound": offprint autographed, 1967 (Box 117, Folder 2878)
    - Ginsberg, Allen
      - "Encounters with Ezra Pound": photocopy autographed, 1985 (Box 117, Folder 2879)
    - Horton, T. David
      - Review of FDR: My Exploited Father-in-Law, by Curtis Dall: typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2880)
    - Hungiville, Maurice
      - "Ezra Pound, Educator: Two Uncollected Pound Letters": offprint, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 2881)
    - Hutchins, Patricia
      - "Thomas Hardy and some Younger Writers": typescript corrected, 1968 (Box 117, Folder 2882)
    - Jones, David
      - [Extract from a letter re The Anathemata ]: typescript, 1952 (Box 117, Folder 2883)
    - Kenner, Hugh
      - "Ezra Pound and the Light of France": offprint autographed (Box 117, Folder 2884)
    - Lamantia, Philip
      - [Poems, including "Politics Poem", "Cool Apocalypse," and "Visions"]: mimeograph, [1967?] (Box 117, Folder 2885)
    - Laughlin, James
      - "A Bit Different": typescript, 1948 (Box 117, Folder 2886)
    - Levy, Alan
      - "Ezra Pound: a Jewish View": printed, 1987 Feb (Box 117, Folder 2887)
    - Levy, William, ed.
      - certain radio speeches of ezra pound: printed photocopy, [1975?] (Box 117, Folder 2888)
    - Lorca, Federico Garcia
      - "Merry-Go-Round...Printed at Christmas, 1980 for the friends of Ann and J. Laughlin and New Directions": printed (Box 117, Folder 2889)
    - Majno, Luigi
      - "Indiscrezioni ovvero Une revue es Duex Mondes": typescript carbon, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 2890)
    - Malanga, Gerard
      - "The 'San Treviso' Notebook": typescript, 1968 (Box 117, Folder 2891)
    - Manca, Marie Antoinette
      - "L'harmonie du chant": typescript photocopy, 1968 (Box 117, Folder 2892)
    - Markham, Virgil
      - "Plan for Study": typescript, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2893)
    - Martin, Philip
      - [Poems]: mimeograph, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2894)
    - Molesworth, Charles
      - Marianne Moore: A Literary Life: photocopies of pages, annotated by Chester Page, signed, [1990?] (Box 117, Folder 2895)
    - O'Grady, Desmond
      - "A Packet for W. B. Yeats from Ezra Pound": outline and partial draft typescript, annotated, 1969 (Box 117, Folder 2896)
    - Palandri, Angela Jung
      - "'The Stone is Alive in My Hand': Ezra Pound's Chinese Translations": offprint, 1966 (Box 117, Folder 2897)
    - Parens, Rachel Anto
      - "Pound Imagined at Spoleto Festival": typescript (Box 117, Folder 2898)
    - Perlman, John
      - "Dinner 950 Warburton Avenue Yonkers: for Jan": typescript autographed, [1971?] (Box 117, Folder 2899)
    - Powe, B. W.
      - "Marshall McLuhan: the Put-On": offprint, 1982 (Box 117, Folder 2900)
    - Rachewiltz, Boris de
      - "Discussioni": offprint, 1959 (Box 117, Folder 2901)
    - Raine, Kathleen
      - Extracts from Defending Ancient Springs: typescript corrected (Box 117, Folder 2902)
    - Rainer, Dachine
      - "At Random: A Few Poems for Olga Rudge": typescript photocopy, 1985 (Box 118, Folder 2903)
      - "Dwelley Farm": typescript photocopy, 1986 (Box 118, Folder 2904)
      - "Ezra Pound, for Olga Rudge": typescript photocopy, 1973